So one of the things that I want to try as we're talking about align-items and
在谈到 align-items 和 justify-content 之前
justify content is how you can use documentation yourself.
我想提到的事情是如何自行查阅文档
It's really impossible to memorize every single type of code there is.
想要记住所有的东西明显是不可能的
Sure, you put your 10,000 hours in and you know a lot of the stuff by heart.
当然 你可以花一万个小时 然后你会对很多知识都了然于心
You pick it up, your fingers start to know the keystrokes.
在你开始写代码时 可能你的手指自动就知道从哪里开始了
But the truth is there's so many properties that even professional developers,
但实际上是 有太多的属性了 即使是专业开发者
often consult the documentation to learn all of them.
也需要经常查看文档来了解不同的属性
So last night, as I was preparing this run through,
所以在昨晚 当我自己在
going through the documentation myself, I thought,
浏览文档时 我想了下
Instead of pretending I'm totally brilliant and just always know this stuff,
我不想装作自己学富五车 啥都知道
I would show some of that process with you and we could share
所以 我会向你展示一些编写代码时的流程 我们会一起查阅文档
the process of looking at documentation as we're working with code.
然后找到所需的知识
So let's see how it goes.
让我们开始吧
Here I'm looking at the justify-content page.
这里是一个关于 justify-content 的文档页面
I can see that the different possibilities for justify-content,
可以看到 justify-content 有不同的属性
are start, center, space between,
start、center、space-between、
space around, and space evenly.
space-around 和 space-evenly 等等
So over here I can tell that I'm using justify-content center,
我们当前使用的是 justify-content center 属性
let's try some of the other ones.
我们再试试其他的选项
What happens if I go justify-content start?
如果我设置 justify-content 为 start 会发生什么？
Boom. Did you see that?
看见没？
All the boxes moved over so that they start where my starting access is.
所有的 box 都从开始位置排成了一行
Should we see it again? There they go, back to center.
让我们再来一遍 先回到 center 状态
Let's take a look at another one.
这次我们试试另一个选项
What would happen if we did space around? Did you see that?
如果设置为 space-around 会发生什么呢？
Now, it evenly distributes that with space in between each of them.
现在 它们均匀地分散排列 并且四周都有空隙
Should we see it again? There it is, centered.
再看一次 回到 center 状态
Here it is, space around.
之前是 space-around
Should we try one more?
这次我们再试试更多的选项
How about space evenly?
试试 space-evenly 吧 ?
Cool. These are only working, if you notice,
不错 生效了 如果你仔细注意一下的话
justify-content is doing things on the horizontal access.
justify-content 改变了元素在水平轴上的布局情况
Let's try some different settings with aligned items.
我们尝试一个不同的属性 align-items
In order to do so, I'm going to create a few more boxes.
为了展示效果 我们创建更多 box
Okay. So now, let's take a look at aligning some items.
好了 现在我们来试试 align-items 属性
So we've added boxes four and five here,
这里我们有了 5 个 box
so we can see boxes 1,
box 1
2, 3, 4, and 5.
2 3 4 还有 5
Here we can see that we have align item set to center.
当前设置的 align-items 属性是 center
If we go into the documentation,
如果我们看看文档的话
we can see that some of the other ones are stretch, start, and end.
可以看到其他的值有 stretch、start、end 等等
So let's take a look at stretch.
我们来试试 stretch 看看发生了什么？
Let's see what happens if we change this to column.
先把这里改为 column
So align items, stretched out,
然后 align-items 设置为 stretch
we see that they're actually going to stretch across
我们可以看到它们拉伸并
the entire width of the container that it's in.
撑满了整行容器宽度
That's one of the amazing things that flex does.
这是弹性盒子强大的能力之一
If you see here, box no longer has any width and height set explicitly on it,
你在这里可以看到 box 没有显式的设置宽度和高度
all it has is a border.
只有一个边框
But simply by changing the way that the items are fit in to the container,
通过简单地改变容器中元素的适应方式
we see them actually change their shape.
我们就可以改变它们的外形
So let's try end.
再试试 end 吧
So now, we have align-items end,
好了 现在 align-items 为 end 了
how about align-items start? That's going to be the theme.
那么 start 状态呢？还是一样
What if we do align-items and in a row?
如果我们设置为 row 呢？
We'll try centered, stretch.
我们试试 center 然后是 stretch
Let's take out justify-content.
我们把 justify-content 注释掉 看看发生什么
See what happens, no change.
还是没有变化
What if we changed the direction of our axes?
如果我们改变一下轴的方向呢？
Now, we see a change.
好了 现在有变化了
So you can see that align-items and justify-content act
所以你可以看到 align-items 和 justify-content 会根据
differently based on the flex direction itself.
flex-direction 而动态变化
Here we have one of what I think is the most comfortable setups that I use.
当前方式是我认为看起来最舒服的一种布局方式
One of the things that I like to see are
我喜欢让这些 box 依次排列
well-distributed boxes that use up as much real estate as possible.
并尽可能地均匀分布 占据所有空间
In this example, we've set up box one through five
在这个例子中 我们让 box 1 到 box 5 的所有元素
to be spaced evenly throughout its parent container.
在父容器之间依次排序 占据整行 元素之间均匀留有空隙
So that even if we took out,
这样的话 即使拿掉 box 5
say box five, we can see now that
可以看到
the four boxes will redistribute themselves to occupy the space.
剩余的 4 个盒子依然是均匀分布状态
Let's say we don't want box three anymore either,
再次拿掉 box 3
you see how this works?
看见了没？
Flexbox presents a lot of magic possibilities,
弹性盒子的灵活性和布局可塑性很强
box one, box four.
box 1 box 4
Still right in the center,
仍然均匀分布在中间
without any extra code,
并不需要额外的代码
we have box one.
box 1 就会居中显示
So a lot of what we've just seen,
我们已经看过很多种情况了
including the way that we remove and add different elements,
包括删除和添加不同的元素
a lot of this stuff can also be done in a programming language called JavaScript.
其实 我们也可以通过 Javscript 来完成所有这些功能
Actually, if you look on the internet,
实际上 如果你上网搜索的话
there's whole sets of people who will argue
经常会有很多人争论哪种语言最好
the best way to do things because JavaScript is
一方面 JavaScript 是
a more complex language that really allows you a dynamic possibility that CSS doesn't.
一门更复杂的语言 可以让你实现很多 CSS 不能完成的功能
But CSS is a much simpler language that also can allow you,
但是 CSS 是一门更简单的语言
as you see to do some of the same things.
通过它 你可以更轻松的完成一些类似的功能
So as you learn both of these tools,
在你掌握了这两种不同的语言之后
you could weigh in on the debate about when and how to use
你可以自由权衡什么时候以及如何
CSS vs JavaScript to manipulate elements on your DOM.
使用 CSS 或 Javascript 来操作你的 DOM 元素